JOE FERNETTE

Web Development

CONTACT

- **989-859-3499**
- Fernettejs@gmail.com
- ■ Github.com/Fernettejs
- Midland, MI

SKILLS

- HTML
- Problem solving
- CSS
- Teamwork
- JavaScript
- Written
- React
- communication
- WordPress
- Interpersonal
- Search Engine
- communication
- Optimization
- Critical thinking
- eCommerce
- Adaptability

PROJECTS

Fernettejs.github.io:

- Online portfolio created from scratch.
- Showcases all personal projects including
 - o Angry Eight Ball
 - o More Cowbell Button
 - o OperationOutlast.com

Efficiency-driven, outcome-oriented web developer focused on creating high-impact, user-centric websites. A creative, self-starter and quick learner with excellent communication, organizational and analytical skills with leadership and problem-solving experience under a vast array of high-pressure environments.

EXPERIENCE

PUBLIC SAFETY OFFICER • BAY CITY DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC SAFETY • 2018 – CURRENT

- Problem solving that required creative thinking in order to solve people's unique issues.
- Attention to detail when writing over 700 reports that have been viewed by supervisors and prosecuting attorneys.
- Collaborated with partners and other agencies daily to resolve problems.

BUSINESS OWNER • OPERATION OUTLAST LLC • 2016-2018

- Personal business built from scratch where I used WordPress to create a website to share information and entertain.
- Used HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to make changes to the WordPress theme and have a responsive design in order to be viable on multiple platforms.
- Included blog posts, imbedded videos, products, and outside commenting that consumers viewed.
- Tested and debugged website while adding plugins for easier use.

UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN • SEE EDUCATION BELOW • 2014-2018

COMBAT ENGINEER • UNITED STATES MARINE CORPS • 2010-2014

- Data collection and analysis with risk assessment covering multiple aspects of the job.
- Critical thinking and decision making in order to approach problems from varying angles.
- Completed Intermediate Leadership and Management Development.
- Supervised, trained and evaluated 25 personnel in rapidly changing environments.

EDUCATION

- CODECADEMY WEB DEVELOPMENT COURSE COMPLETED 2020
- UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN B.A. PSYCHOLOGY GRADUATED 2018
 - O 3.2 GPA. Data entry / Research / Problem solving